# DEVIN KENT



dalamcd@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/devinkent



615-589-2483



github.com/dalamcd

## FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a lover of technology and long-time hobbyist programmer of 15 years. After developing my leadership, team-building, and problem solving skills in the service industry, I decided to follow my passion for development and enroll in Nashville Software School to start on my professional journey. With a solid foundation in coding and logic, I have an intrinsic ability to pick up and adapt to new technologies and frameworks quickly, communicate clearly, and solve problems in the simplest, most efficient way.

At NSS, I have had the opportunity to work one-on-one with many of my classmates, helping them to find the simplest solution to their coding roadblocks. This type of work has helped me grow as a programmer, learning to deploy efficient code of my own as well as troubleshoot, debug and manage existing software.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- Python
- React
- Diango
- CSS3 - HTML
- PHP
- SOL
- C#

# **EDUCATION**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Development Bootcamp - Certificate

## **TECHNICAL EDUCATION**

#### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

#### Software Development Bootcamp

September 2020 - March 2021

An intensive six month lab focused on full-stack software development, creating applications individually and team based projects using modern industry technologies

- Developed dynamic single page applications using React and JavaScript ES6
- Learned fundamentals of HTML, CSS, JSON, REST, modular development, database management, and reusable code
- Exposure to Agile development with daily standups, planning using tickets, and group assignments
- Used GitHub for version control, using pull requests to manage projects and merge

#### **GROUP PROJECTS**

#### NUTSHELL - github.com/nss-day-cohort-44/nutshell-labyrinth-leprechauns

Nutshell is a JavaScript application where users can create and manage events, tasks, news and chat messages. They can share these with other users they have added as friends. I was responsible for implementing a widget to view weather for a given date using an external API, the chat feature including private messages to other users, and the list of events.

#### HOLIDAY ROAD - github.com/nss-day-cohort-44/holiday-road-barringer-crater

Holiday Road is a vanilla JavaScript application for creating and planning road trips. Users can pick from a selection of national parks, attractions, and restaurants, and receive a list of driving directions to each of them. I was responsible for working with the external Graphhopper API to build and display the directions, as well as generating the lists of attractions and restaurants from stored data.

#### **SOLO PROJECTS**

#### SIMULACRUM - https://github.com/dalamcd/simulacrum

Simulacrum is a single page React application where visitors can interact with and ask questions of a panel of "simulated AI" characters--famous names from history and fiction. Administrators can create new characters with associated avatar images, and use these characters to answer questions that visitors have asked in the form of a conversation between famous personalities.

# **WORK HISTORY**

#### **BLUE COAST BURRITO**

2008 - 2018

Assistant Manager

- Responsible for supervising, hiring and training of all
- · Created automated scheduling software for managing staff schedules

## **SERVICE SOURCE**

2019 - 2020

Inside Sales Representative

- Managed a multi-million dollar sales territory
- Created multiple Excel macros and sheets to increase team productivity